# **Ernesto Crespo**

**Data Scientist** 

I'm a Data Scientist with more than +20 year of experience as a Python developer with Knowledge in Linux. I have experience developing API restful, working in data cleaning in Advanced Exploratory Data analysis, and working as AWS Cloud Engineer. I'm looking for a remote position as a Data Scientist with Machine learning, and deep learning technologies in the health-technology, EduTech, InsurTech, or Renewable Energy sectors.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Asistensi Global Insurance, Inc, Software Engineer III— October 2021 - Present

- Reduce response times by fixing bugs and supporting services for the medical emergency management tool.
- Improve by 60% the medical prescription service for Asistensi clients in Mexico by designing and developing Medikit API integration with EMS.
- Enhance 50% (only backend for now) of Engineer software process in Emergency Management Systems EMS by developing Python Clean code validation.

**Tech Stack**: Django, Django-rest framework, PostgreSQL, Docker, AWS Lambda, Python, pandas, NumPy.

## Escala24x7, AWS Cloud Engineer — August 2019 - October 2021

- Improved by 80% the care attention by developing AWS APIs and automating the Escala customer service.
- Enhanced 90% of searches for bank customer calls by developing a Data lake for the call system of Banesco.
- Improved 80% of consults vehicle credit sales queries and customer delinquency by developing a Data lake parsing data from the vehicle monitoring system.

**Tech Stack:** Python, pandas, NumPy, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, lambda, cloud watch Event, SNS, SQS, AWS API, Step functions, cloud formation, AWS SAM, AWS Athena, AWS Glue, AWS Redshift.

#### Troc Global, BI Developer — July 2018 - August 2019

Accelerated decision-making of the company's management by developing modules and APIs for EDA, PCA, and
predictive analysis as a decision-making tool in the management of electronic and mobile equipment sales
stores in Walmart establishments.

**Tech Stack:** Python, pandas, NumPy, sci-kit-learn, pyMC3, matplotlib, Seaborn, Django-rest framework, PostgreSQL, and rethinkDB.

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Advanced: Python; Basic: R, Pyspark, javascript.

**Frameworks Tools:** Advanced: Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, bokeh; Intermediate: Scipy, scikit-learn, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Strreamlit; Basic: Scrapy, Tensorflow, pyMC3, NLTK, Spacy, Pytest, Redis.

Data Base: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, MySQL, AWS RDS.

Tools: Tableu, Google Data Studio, Docker, Linux.

Agile: Scrum, Extreme Programming.

Languages: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

## **EDUCATION**

**University of Carabobo** – Valencia, Electrical Engineer, December 2001.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Inferential Statistics with R - Platzi. 2021.

Spark Basics for Big Data - Platzi. 2021.

Machine Learning with scikit-learn - Platzi. 2021.

Google Data Studio - Platzi. 2021.

**Tableu: Data visualization and Storytelling for Business** – Platzi. 2021.

Machine Learning with Python (Practice introduction) – EDX/IBM. 2019.

**Analyzing Data with Python** – EDX/IBM. 2020.

**Data Engineer with Python** – Platzi. 2020.

Introduction to PySpark - Datacamp. 2020.

AWS Redshift for handling Big Data - Platzi. 2020.